

Av. de Valdemarin 91A 1°D, 28023, Madrid, Spain

□ (+34) 651 808 171 | work@pabloforero.eu | www.pabloforero.eu | pforero | pforero

Summary _

Data Scientist at Allfunds' Innovation Lab. Strong analytical and technological skills. Specialist in modelling and predictive analysis. Stochastic models, time series, dynamic programming, machine learning and neural networks. Enthusiast of free open source software and modern industry practices.

Work Experience_

Allfunds Madrid, Spain

DATA SCIENTIST, INNOVATION LAB 2018 - Present

- · Italian costumers with forest.
- NLP prospectus.
- · Salesforce.
- · Datalake, Google cloud, BigQuery
- Minerva
- · Daily email.
- · Eva.
- Arcus

SAIS John Hopkins University

Bologna, Italy

TEACHING ASSISTANT 201

• Teaching assistant in International Trade for Professor G. Plummer.

Banif (Santander Private Banking) Madrid, Spain

ANALYST, ASSET MANAGEMENT

2009 - 2010

- Support/Analysis.
- Fixed Income.

Renaissance Capital London, UK

INTERN, RESEARCH

2008

• Sub-saharan Emerging Markets.

CQS Hedge Fund London, UK

INTERN, RESEARCH

2008

· Pension Plans.

ING Capital London, UK

INTERN, RESEARCH

2007

· Easter European Emerging Markets.

Education

European University Institute Florence, Italy

Ph.D. (ABD) IN ECONOMICS

2012 - 2017

- Thesis title: Competition, Tasks and Earnings Inequality
- Supervisor: Ramon Marimón

European University Institute Florence, Italy

MRES IN ECONOMICS 2013

Universidad de Navarra Pamplona, Spain

MSC IN ECONOMICS AND FINANCE 2011

University of Exeter Exeter, UK

B.A. IN ECONOMICS AND POLITICS 2006 - 2009

Professional Activities

EABCN Training School Florence, Italy

2016

2016

Participant

• Micro-Structure of Trade - Theory and Evidence

• Taught by Klaus Adam

Workshop on Economic Policy Challenges Florence, Italy

DISCUSSANT

• The Optimal Inflation Rate and Firm-Level Productivity Trends

• By Klaus Adam and Henning Weber

The Econometric Society 2016 European Winter Meeting Edinburgh, UK

Presenting 2016

Simposio de la Asociación Española de Economía

Bilbao, Spain

Presenting 2016

Zurich Initiative on Computational Economics Zurich, Switzerland

Participant 2015

COEURE Workshop on Labour Markets

Brussels, Belgium

RAPPORTFUR 2015

• EU Dual Labour Markets: Consequences and Potential Reforms

Skills_

Research International Trade, Macroeconomics, Labour Economics, Computational Economics

Languages Spanish, English, French (Basic), Italian (Basic)

Programming Languages Python, Matlab, SQL, LaTeX, Julia, VBA

Statistical Tools Excel, Dynare, Eviews, Stata

Cloud Tools BigQuery, Google Storage, Composer **Tools** Docker, Sphinx, Git, Office, Airflow, PyTorch